



USHIR RANJAN USHIR RANJAN (Featured) System Engineer seeking roles in IT Project Management, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Solution Designing, Design Patterns, Core Java, Spring, Javascript, SQL, Maven, Spring, Python, machine learning, Nlp, Flask framework, Tableau. Current Designation: System Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 1 Month(s) Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Notice Period: 1 Month Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Mechanical] Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Role: System Admin Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Single/unmarried Key Skills: System Engineer, System Admin, IT Project Management, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Solution Designing, Structured Programming, Design Patterns, OOD, Core Java, Spring, SQL, Advanced Java, Python, Machine Learning

Last Active: 20-Jan-21

Verified : Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

A Professional having experience over 2.10+ years as Java Developer and Data Scientist having rich knowledge in Core Java, Advanced Java., Python, Machine Learning, Statistical Concept, and NLP. Working experience and extensive knowledge in Python and libraries such as Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL Server, data mining quality. I am very familiar and experienced with Web Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as System Engineer

Dec 2017 to Till Date

Client

US Bank

Domain

Banking

Duration

May 2019 - Present

Role

Worked as a Java Developer implementing various Business logic to enhance the User experience on various channels. Also worked on Accessibility defects.

Client

AMEX (American Express Company)

Domain

Banking Duration

April, 2018 - May, 2019

Role

Worked as a Java Developer implementing various Business logic to enhance the User experience on various channels. Also worked on Accessibility defects for inspecting, cleansing, transforming, and modeling data with the goal of discovering useful information, suggesting conclusions, and supporting decision-making.

Client

Rubix & Datamites

Domain

Multiple Domain(DataScience)

Duration

May2020 - Present

Role

Worked as a Data Scientist to implementing Business Problems and creating the model to enhance the User experience on various channels. Gather the data from the more available resource's while implementing the tool like Sql, server, oracle and more. Data cleaning is the key role to make the data more effectively and more meaningful. Thereafter the whole worked to provide the better solution with the great accuracy to make the model more interactive.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

WORK RESPONSIBILITIES:

Requirement gathering and analysis.

Technical Design Documentation and Solution development.

Involved in Data Preprocessing Techniques for making the data useful for creating Machine Learning models Experience in Data Preparation, Exploratory Data Analysis, Predictive modelling, Statistics, Machine Learning Techniques

Work with large, complex data sets; solve difficult, non-routine analysis problems, applying advanced analytical methods as needed.

Worked with developer team to identify the use cases for machine learning in enterprise product.

Communicate predictions and findings to Stakeholders through effective data visualizations and reports.

Involved in creating a model for predicting the sales for House Price based on Location various availability and services ,Sentiment Analysis based on the Customer reviews, Classification Problems (Banking Fraud Detection) and the ITSM Ticket Management services.

Also provided internal corporate training within the company for Data Science, ML and Deep Learning and NLP.

Executing test cases and fixing bugs through Unit Testing.

Integrating the module with other modules and deploying them.

Leading team during innovative iterations and presenting various application enhancements.

Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleague.

Work with experienced team members to conduct root cause analysis of issues, review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Mechanical) from Siddaganga Institute Of Technology (VTU) in 2017

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience Core Java, Advanced Java, spring Python, Pandas , Numpy, Matplottib Skleam, Neural Network SpringMvC, Springboot, Flask HTML, CSS SQL server, Mysql, Oracle DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder IDE Pycham, Eclipse, Intellij, Tableau AGILE				
Python, Pandas ,Numpy, Matplotlib Skleam, Neural Network SpringMvC,Springboot, Flask HTML,CSS SQL server, Mysql,Oracle DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook,Spyder IDE Pycham,Eclipse,Intellij,Tableau	Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Skleam, Neural Network SpringMvC,Springboot, Flask HTML,CSS SQL server, Mysql,Oracle DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook,Spyder IDE Pycham,Edipse,Intellij,Tableau	Core Java, Advanced Java, spring			
SpringMC,Springboot, Flask HTML,CSS SQL server, Mysql,Oracle DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook,Spyder IDE Pycham,Eclipse,Intellij,Tableau	Python, Pandas ,Numpy, Matplotlib			
HTML,CSS SQL server, Mysql,Oracle DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook,Spyder IDE Pycham,Edipse,Intellij,Tableau	Sklearn, Neural Network			
SQL server, Mysql,Orade DB Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook,Spyder IDE Pycham,Edipse,Intellij,Tableau	SpringMVC,Springboot, Flask			
Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder IDE Pycham, Eclipse, Intellij, Tableau	HTML,CSS			
Pycham, Edipse, Intellij, Tableau	SQL server, Mysql,Oracle DB			
	Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder IDE			
AGILE	Pycham,Eclipse,Intellij,Tableau			
	AGILE			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.